Guide to the Henry Major Tomlinson Papers, 1873-1958
Department of Special Collections
Henry Major Tomlinson Papers,
1873-1958
Special Collections M0318
Tomlinson, Henry Major, 1873-1958
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased from Dr. J. Tufts, 1979
Biography
Henry Major Tomlinson, born 1873 in Essex, England, was a novelist, essayist, travel writer, and journalist. He died 5 February 1958 in London.
Scope and Content
Collection includes letters, newsclippings, and articles by and about Tomlinson and his work. Also included is a holograph manuscript of "That Next War," a typescript of "A Complaint of Peace," and a first edition of "A Complaint of Peace" in San Francisco Chronicle (1929).
Container List
- Letters to Dr. Tufts from book dealers (John Gurlson, London) re: Tomlinson and his work. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous newsclippings by and about Tomlinson. 1920-1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous newsclippings by and about Tomlinson. 1920-1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Newsclips and journal articles re: Tomlinson and his books. 1920-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Newsclips and journal articles re: Tomlinson and his books. 1920-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Two journal articles re: Tomlinson and his works. 1923, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Two journal articles 1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photoflow prints of newsclips written by Tomlinson. Originally bound in black, 3-ring binder. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Second part of binder contents, listed above. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Holograph manuscript, signed, of "That next war." 22 leaves, 8 vo., in ink, heavily corrected with original protrait photograph of Tomlinson laid in. Paper folder. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Typescript, signed, of "A complaint of peace." 6 leaves, 8 vo, corrected in ink, with original ink portrait of Tomlinson, als, 1p 2 envelopes, and 2 newspaper clippings, all tipped or mounted onto vellum, bound in full red levant morocco. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- First edition of " A complaint of Peace, " in San Francisco Chronicle. 1929, Dec 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)